A little pause... and we are back.
What?
What does this mean?
A man?
A person?
Oh no!
This is a summoning jutsu!
Naruto!
Sakura!
Quick!
Get rid of the scrolls!
What?
It's you?
Hey.
Long time no see.
Long time no see, huh?
Congratulations!
You passed the second exam!
To celebrate your passing, I would love to
treat you all to some Ichiraku ramen,
but I... Ramen?
Seriously?
That's so cool!
Wait!
I'm not done!
So cool!
Let go!
Hey, Naruto!
Oh yeah!
Ramen would be awesome!
Especially after all the bugs and plants
we've had to eat for the past two days!
So great!
Yeah!
I'm gonna eat every noodle ever made!
Where does he get all his energy?
Yeah!
Shut up!
Alright.
Well, I can see you're still as
hyperactive as ever, Naruto.
Oh yeah, Sensei.
Yeah?
What does that writing on the wall mean?
The parchment the
letters are written on is
kinda eaten away, so
it's difficult to read it.
We can't understand it.
Oh please!
Look, we passed, didn't we?
That stuff doesn't matter now!
Well...
Actually, explaining
that is another one of the
duties that I've been
sent here to take care of.
Hm?
What, seriously?
That's right.
It's serious business.
Give it a good read.
They're instructions Lord Hokage recorded
as principles that Chunin should follow.
They're instructions?
Yes.
Heaven stands for your mind and earth for
your body.
If qualities of heaven are your desire,
acquire wisdom to take your mind higher.
Get it?
Mmm... mm-mm.
Alright, I'll explain.
In other words, if your weakness lies in
your intellect, Naruto, then you have to
make doubly sure that you work
hard to learn all the information
and skills that you need to
prepare for your missions.
Ugh... okay, I get your point.
And you.
If earthly qualities you lack,
train your body, prepare to attack.
So if your weakness lies in your physical
strength, Sakura, then you have to make
sure that you work on
your physical conditioning
every single day so it
improves your ability to fight.
When heaven and earth
are open together, the
perilous path will
become righteous forever.
Meaning, if your mind and
body are working together as one,
then even a very dangerous
mission can become an easy one.
So what about that spot with the missing
letter?
Well, that part is meant for all of you to
fill in.
Do you see that symbol on the scroll?
It's the character for person,
a reference to you, Chunin.
You see, these five days
of survival were to test your
abilities as Chunin and to
see if you'd be any good at it.
And I gotta say, you guys really did
magnificently.
A Chunin is a leader, a guide.
It's a Chunin's responsibility
to be aware of the
strengths and weaknesses
of those serving under him.
And to know what skills
and training those ninja
are going to need in order
to succeed on a mission.
You did an excellent job
on this mission and I want
you to remember these
instructions on your next one.
Well, that's it.
That was everything I was supposed to say
to you.
One more thing.
For the third exam, don't push it too far.
Especially you.
Naruto, I worry... Iruka-sensei!
When I got this headband, I stopped being
a student!
So you don't need to worry about me at
all!
Not anymore!
Right now!
I'm a ninja too!
Naruto, you're right.
I'm sorry about that.
Look, I know their strengths and
weaknesses better than anyone else does.
Whatever the result, I want to be the one
who breaks the news to them.
Fine, if you're that hung up on it.
Then I'll just leave that team in your
hands.
But I would have thought you'd have a
little more confidence in them, you know?
Thank you, Anko.
Wait, those guys are Kakashi's students,
aren't they?
Listen, if Kakashi's got faith in them,
then I wouldn't count them out just yet,
Iruka.
It seems to me now that the one who truly
understands the strengths and weaknesses
of these young ninja best might very well
be you, Kakashi.
Ugh...
How is it?
Does the curse mark still cause you pain?
No, not really.
Thanks to you, it's much better.
That's good, but we better get back to
business.
This Orochimaru is one of the Sannin,
the legendary Three Ninja, isn't he?
He's supposed to be so
incredibly powerful that not
even the Anbu Black Ops
unit could bring him down.
I'd heard a rumor that he died,
but I guess that wasn't true.
Why did he come to this village now,
anyway?
He's after Sasuke, right?
What?
Anko, we've confirmed that 21 ninja have
finished the second exam.
And as for the third exam,
according to the rules,
we'll have to hold a
round of preliminaries first.
The first time in five years.
Now, for the time being, we'll just
continue with the exams as planned.
But I also want to keep an eye on his
movements as well.
Yes.
First of all, congratulations on finishing
the second exam!
Huh.
There were 78 ninja who took that exam.
Frankly, I'm surprised that even 21
passed.
I knew that less than half
would make it, but I really
thought the number
would be in the single digits.
I'm really hungry.
What a drag.
There's so many left.
This is such a pain.
Sasuke and his team have passed,
too!
Well, of course they did.
I see your team didn't do too bad,
Kakashi.
They must have gotten real lucky.
Of course, with my team still around,
your team is doomed to failure.
After all, what matters
on the next test is
ability, and we've
got you far outclassed.
Well, I guess that
part of growing up is
learning to deal with
heartbreak, huh, Kakashi?
Hm?
Did you say something?
Alright, Kakashi, you win this round.
Boy, that drives me nuts when you act so
cool.
There's no way I'm gonna let you get the
best of me.
So that's Gai-sensei's old rival,
huh?
Well, if I had to judge them on looks
alone, I'd say Gai-sensei would lose.
Gai-sensei is just the coolest teacher
ever!
I mean, he is so cool, he practically
glows with cool!
You watch, Gai-sensei!
Someday I'll make you proud of me!
Lord Hokage, they're all yours.
Hm.
Very well, then.
Now listen closely.
I'm going to tell you exactly what you'll
all be doing on the third exam.
Huh?
Lord Hokage, before you do, please allow
me, Hayate Genji... ...Echo to speak first.
So be it.
There's something I would like all of
you...
...to do before the third exam.
Uh... we have to have a preliminary exam
before we can move on to... the real one.
Huh?
A what?
Preliminary?
Just what do you mean by that?
Uh... well, you see... The first and
second exams might have been too easy.
The fact is, we never expected so many of
you to still be here.
According to the rules of the Chunin
exams, a preliminary round can be held at
any stage, in order to reduce the number
of candidates remaining.
But... is that fair?
We have to speed things up a bit.
A lot of important guests will be
watching.
We can't afford to waste their time.
They've come to see only the best.
So if there are any of you who feel you're
not in top physical condition,
now's your chance to...
Sorry about that.
As I was saying, any of you who don't feel
up to this...
Now's the time for you to bow out.
The preliminaries will be starting
immediately.
Come on!
You mean right now?
We just finished barely surviving the last
exam!
Don't we get a break?
Man, what a drag.
Eh... when do we eat?
Well, they pulled a fast one.
But I'm in.
All the way.
No matter what.
I gave my word to Kabuto.
Okay.
You got me.
I'm out.
Kabuto Yakushi of the Leaf Village,
right?
Okay.
You can go on and step back.
Gotcha.
Kabuto!
Hold on a second!
You can't quit!
I don't get this!
What's going on?
Oh, Naruto.
I'm sorry.
But my body's just too beat up.
I can't hack it.
The fact is, ever since orientation and
that dust-up with the Sound Village team.
..
I've had no hearing at all in my left ear.
And now to have to put my life on the
line?
To fight again?
Right away without a break?
I can't do it.
Seems to me I've seen that one before.
Anko?
Oh, right.
Kabuto Yakushi.
Says here he's... failed six times in a
row.
What do you have on his background?
His time at the Academy was not what you'd
call impressive.
Average grades.
Took him a full three tries before he
passed the graduation exam.
As far as the missions
he's carried out since then,
there's been two C ranks
and fourteen D ranks.
It's not exactly a battle record to write
home about.
However...
Go on.
Do you remember the child?
The one who was found after the Battle of
Kikyo Pass?
The only survivor?
I remember the story.
It was said a small boy was found among
the enemy dead on the battlefield.
He was found barely alive and brought back
by a Jonin from the medical unit.
You're saying this is that boy?
Yes.
With you here looking after things, you
don't need me, do you, Lord Orochimaru?
Guess I'll just have to save my fun for
later.
Until we meet again, Sasuke.
Oh.
And you too, of course.
Naruto.
Waves of pain!
They're coming sooner and sooner!
Oh no!
I knew it!
Sasuke!
Listen to me!
You have got to quit!
Huh?
You've been like this ever since you tangled
with Orochimaru, and it's getting worse!
Please... Please, Sasuke,
quit now before...
I don't know what... I'm scared...
Come on, you know as well as I do,
you're in no condition to keep on fighting!
Shut up, Sakura!
You think I'm blind or something?
Will you please be quiet?
You think I don't see the suffering you're
going through?
That's enough, Sakura.
I'm sorry.
I can't let you do it to yourself.
I'm going to tell them about that mark.
Then maybe you'll...
Don't you even think of telling them about
this mark.
I don't get what you're trying to prove.
Am I supposed to just stand by and watch
you tear yourself apart?
I can't bear to watch it.
Then don't watch, but stay out of it.
This has nothing to do with you.
For me, this is something far more than
just an exam.
Whether I become a Chunin or not means
less than nothing to me.
Am I as strong as I can be?
All I want is the answer to that.
I can only find out by fighting the
strongest.
The best.
And the best of the best... are all here.
This is the path I walk.
Not you or anyone can change that.
Oh, Sasuke.
Man, you don't know when to quit!
What are you biting your head off for,
you idiot?
It's just because she cares about you!
Naruto.
Huh?
You're one of the ones I want to fight the
most.
Huh?
It's just as I feared.
What do we do with him?
We take him out of the
exam, hand him over to
Black Ops, and let them
keep him locked up.
We have to keep that seal under control...
Oh, and he's just going to quietly go
along with all of this, huh?
You really think so?
You're forgetting.
He's of the Uchiha clan.
I don't care what the heck he is!
If he stays, he's a danger to everyone!
Allow the boy to continue with the exam
for now.
What?
And we'll see what happens.
But, Lord Hokage...
However, at the first sign of
the curse mark growing or his
power getting out of control,
you will step in and stop it.
Right.
All right, then.
We'll now begin the preliminary round.
This round will consist of one-on-one
individual combat at full battle intensity.
This is not an exercise.
There are twenty of you remaining,
so that means we will need ten matches.
The surviving candidates from these ten
matches will advance to the third exam.
As for the rules, there are none.
You will fight until one
dies or concedes defeat, or is
rendered physically incapable
of continuing the contest.
Naturally, those who
are losing are urged to
concede defeat promptly
to avoid a fatal outcome.
Furthermore, as Proctor, I'm given a certain
amount of leeway in judging the matches.
I might occasionally
intervene if a match seems
hopeless, to save as
many lives as possible.
Now it's time to reveal what fate has been
chosen for you.
Open the panel.
The names of each pair of opponents are
chosen completely at random.
Before each match, these names will appear
on the display behind me.
As there's nothing more to say,
let's begin.
In a moment, the names of the first two
opponents will appear.
Hmph.
Didn't waste any time, did they?
I couldn't ask for anything more.
No!
Why did it have to be Sasuke?
Alright now.
Those whose names have been drawn,
come forward.
You have been chosen for the first match.
Yoroi Okado and Sasuke Uchiha.
Are there any objections?
None here.
No.
Hmph.
The pain won't go away.
That curse mark giving you trouble.
Okay.
Everyone other than the
two opposing candidates
will now clear the area
and move to the upper level.
Hey!
Kakashi-sensei!
Sasuke.
Don't use your shotgun.
So you know about it.
If that mark on your neck gets out of
control, your life could be in danger.
I'm aware of that.
Just to let you
know, if it gets to that
point, I'll have to step
in and stop the fight.
Good luck.
Stop the fight?
This thing... it seems to be responding to
my chakra.
I've got to fight him without using my
Sharingan.
And even my own jutsu is off limits.
Maybe I can make him laugh himself to
death.
The thing is, Sasuke.
Yoroi's unique skills are going to be
disastrous for you.
Then if you're ready, let the match begin.
Oh, I'm ready.
So am I.
Ah!
Already?
Really?
What's happening?
All my strength!
Suddenly it's gone!
My chakra!
You're stealing it from me!
You finally caught on, huh?
That's right, Sasuke.
He's draining your chakra.
Yoroi has an extraordinary ninja art at
his fingertips.
He can absorb an opponent's spiritual and
physical energy with the palm of his hand.
And once the last drop of your chakra has
been drained from you, Sasuke,
you'll have no other choice but to refuse.
Rely on the power of the Curse Mark.
Get off me!
So, you've still got some strength left,
huh?
Impressive.
For a guinea pig.
Hey, Sasuke!
Come on, man!
What was that?
And you call yourself an Uchiha?
You're gonna let this goon walk all over
you!
Come on!
Stop messing around and get it in gear!
Wait!
That's it!
I'll teach you to turn your back on me!
Is this as far as it goes?
That's my move!
Huh?
Okay, I admit it.
I kind of borrowed that move.
But from here on in, it's all original.
No!
I won't let this thing take over!
No way!
Sasuke!
Here we go.
Huh?
I can do this!
Well,
this one's had it.
I'm apples and oranges right away.
Declaring this match over.
As the winner of this preliminary round,
Sasuke Uchiha advances to the finals.
Way to go!
Hmm.
Not bad.
Funny, before the Lion's
Barrage, your technique
was very reminiscent
of Gai's taijutsu.
You okay?
Hey, Sasuke!
You won, but in such an uncool way!
You came out looking like you're the one
who got beat up!
Idiot.
Give me a break,
you little... Oh well.
Sasuke, thank goodness.
I can't wait until it's my turn!
Hmm.
Impressive.
Bet you can't expect
to master high-speed
taijutsu and lotus
movements just like that.
It takes more than shotgun.
It takes blood, and sweat, and brutal
training that whittles away your flesh.
Even so, that last
move of yours... Hmm.
He reminds me of you, Kakashi.
When you were young.
Well, well.
So that's how it's done.
I knew all the time he'd be okay!
Hahaha!
You're out of the line for us.
Man, I'm hungry.
Wow!
He was amazing!
Ah, it wasn't anything that special.
Magnificent!
Sasuke Uchiha.
Maybe you should come along to the infirmary,
too, and let us treat your injuries.
I think you're out of your league with
this one.
Huh?
I'll look after him.
Okay, up you go.
You're coming with me.
We've got to seal that curse mark.
Before the preliminaries are over?
I want to see who gets to go on to the
finals.
Forget it.
But... And don't
even think of arguing.
If we leave it any longer, who knows,
it may be too late.
I've already cut you enough slack as it
is.
Come on, let's go.
...
Uh, okay then.
Let's move right on to the second match.
Hah!
Which sucker is that?
Step forward, please.
Very good.
Now, if you're both ready, then we'll
begin.
How's he going to fight with those arms?
...
Candidates ready?
Begin.
Well, Zaku, how you pull this one off will
be a sight to see.
If you fight me, you won't be able to
recover.
Forfeit and withdraw.
Heh.
Well, what do you know?
I've got a little movement in one of them.
...
One good arm's more than enough to beat
you!
... Heh!
...
You couldn't beat me using both your arms.
Yeah, well, I've got news for ya!
...
Try this!
... I'll slice it that way!
... ...
...
Lmao!
Nope.
No, I got this!
...
Curs ceiling!
Mate, wake up!!
Good evening.
Darkother!
I've been waiting for you, Doctor.
There.
Now the next time that curse mark starts
acting up, the seal should keep it in check.
But remember, this curse-sealing jutsu is
only as strong as you are.
It derives its power from the strength of
your will.
If that will ever weakens,
if you ever begin to doubt
yourself, the curse will
be unleashed in all its fury.
Hmph.
Amazing.
Too tired to even argue.
My, how you've grown.
To think you've become strong enough to
perform the curse-sealing jutsu.
You.
Long time no see, Kakashi.
Orochimaru.
No offense, Kakashi, but I didn't come to
see you.
My business is with that boy behind you.
What do you want with Sasuke?
You've acquired something new.
How I envy your good fortune.
I don't believe you had it the last time
we met.
It's only fair that I should want it too.
The Uchiha power.
All right, fool!
You had enough?
Huh?!
Hmph!
Ah!
Hmmph!
He's got bugs coming out of him,
like a human hive!
There are rare species of parasitic beetle
that attack their prey in a swarm,
eating its chakra.
An army of this size will suck you dry in
less than a minute.
If you use your good arm against me,
my friends will swarm you from behind.
Conversely, if you use
your good arm to keep them
at bay, then you'll have
me on your blind side.
Either way, your defeat will be certain...
and unpleasant.
It's wise to always have an ace in the
hole.
You get the message, you little punk?
You have potential, boy.
If you leave this place and come with me,
I will make you strong, boy.
Follow me.
Come with me, and I will make you strong.
That's it.
That's never gonna happen again!
Now you've done it!
Now you've made me mad!
Like you said yourself...
Always have an ace in the hole.
Right?
So it was just a ploy to make us believe
he had only one good arm.
Clever move.
What's your game?
This sound village that everyone's curious
about?
It's mine.
You see, I created it.
But to play the game, as you put it,
I need pieces on the chessboard.
Willing pawns to do my bidding.
I'll blow you away!
And Sasuke is one of your pawns?
Oh, not a pawn.
He's a far more valuable piece than that.
But as for the others... Well, you
know how it is in the game of chess.
Pieces must be sacrificed.
My arms!
What's wrong with them?
Earlier, while I was distracting you with
my helpful advice, I was also sending some
of my little friends to plug up those
bothersome wind holes in your hands.
Both hands, just to be sure.
You see, while an ace in the hole is
good...
Two aces are better.
Aaaaaah!
Aaaaaaah!
Aaaaah!
Stop!
Don't come any closer!
I don't care if you are one of the Sunny.
I swear.
Take one more step towards Sasuke,
and one of us will die here!
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Funny, is it?
Poor Kakashi.
All your noble efforts, all in vain.
What?
Do you really believe that the seal will
hold?
Do you think you can keep him?
From what he truly desires?
You know I'm right.
A heart like his, that hungers for only
one thing, will not be denied.
No matter what obstacles you put
in his path... He's an Avenger, isn't he?
You think you can take advantage of that?
Not Sasuke.
You cannot stop it.
At some point he will come to me...
In search of power.
Unless, of course, you carry out your
threat to kill me.
Now is your chance.
Take it, if you dare.
Huh... One of us will die here.
It must have been out of my mind.
Aaaaaaah!
I'd say this one... has had it.
The winner is Shino Aburame.
Wait!
How did he do that?
Who is he?
Find out!
Byakugan!
I had no idea.
I thought he must be using a summoning
jutsu to get all those insects.
But no.
They're actually living inside of him.
Living inside of him?
There's a legend in the leaf village of a
clan of insect tamers.
Yes, I've heard of that clan as well.
They say that when a bug master is born...
he enters into a sacred pact with the
insects.
He allows them to nest in his body.
In return, they obey their host's will.
So this guy is one of them?
One of these bug tamers?
I can't pretend we had anything in common,
except this team and our mission.
Still, I'll even the score for you,
Zaku.
Oh, my.
It's getting chilly in here.
Man, that Shino is good!
Who would have thunk it with him being so
quiet?
I can't wait to get my shot at him!
Wow, I thought Shino was weird before,
but now...
Oh, wow, I... congratulations,
Shino!
Way to go!
Good work!
Just see that you two do the same.
Yeah?
Who died and made you team leader,
huh?
Uh, alright, everyone.
Moving right on to the third match.
Kakashi-sensei!
Hi.
What do you mean, hi?
Is that all you can say?
What about... what about Sasuke?
How is he?
Oh, he's fine.
Sleeping soundly in the infirmary.
But he's been put under guard by the Anbu
Black Ops.
Heh.
Finally.
My turn.
Careful, Kankuro.
You'll underestimate your opponent one
time too many.
Hmph.
Idiot.
This guy!
I'm not like Yoroi.
I don't get careless.
Not even against kids.
Heh.
A piece of advice.
Once I go into my jutsu, give up.
Quick.
If you do, I promise to make it short and
painless.
Funny.
I was about to say the same thing.
Hey.
I strike!
Shorvik-tani!
I dislocate every one of my joints,
softening my body.
Then, with my chakra, I can control it
perfectly.
The more you struggle, the tighter I'll
squeeze.
I don't know what you're carrying in
there.
But as long as I have a hold of you,
it makes no difference.
I could break your neck right now if I
wanted to.
And I will, unless you give up.
You wanna bet you'll die?
You fool.
You're the one who's gonna die here.
I think he broke... his neck.
Really?
Too bad he didn't surrender.
Oh well.
Now, it's my turn, so say goodbye.
This is just a puppet!
And the real ninja was in there,
controlling it!
He's a puppet master!
Enough!
I give up!
But if your bones are all crushed, just
think how much more flexible you'll be.
That was close.
I almost stopped the match in the middle.
But it's a good thing I didn't.
Because his opponent is unable to
continue, the winner is Konkuro.
Two against one is hitting below the belt,
isn't it?
I mean, is that thing even fair,
Kakashi-sensei?
It's not really two against one.
It's a puppet, not another ninja.
Yeah, it's just the puppet master jutsu.
He's controlling the puppet with chakra.
It's a ninja tool, like a shuriken.
Now let's continue.
It's time to begin the fourth battle.
No matter who's picked, it'll be two
weirdos.
This contest is chock full of them.
Well, you're one to talk.
Yeah, good point.
Hey!
Give me a break!
This isn't a time for laughter.
I never thought I'd fight you.
Or at least I didn't think it would happen
this soon.
But don't expect me to go easy on you.
I'm sorry, Sakura.
Ino was a standout among the rookie female
shinobi, so she has a good chance to win.
But with Sakura as her opponent, can she
bring herself to fight hard enough to do it?
Of all the people for Ino to go up
against, it would have to be Sakura.
What a mess.
I know.
I hope Ino will be okay.
Let's all hope.
So what's it gonna be, Ino?
Go Sakura!
You can do it!
Don't lose!
Begin.
I'm just not very good at this kind of
stuff.
What about you?
That's not good considering you're named
after a cherry blossom.
Okay, look, it's simple.
I'll explain it, alright?
The first thing is, find a main flower for
your bouquet.
Then you find other flowers that
complement the main one.
You see, flowers have to hide.
They highlight each other's beauty.
There's really nothing to it once you know
all the tricks.
For example, look.
You see those cosmos flowers over there?
Well, if they were the main
flowers in your arrangement, then
the thorough wart flowers you
picked would complement them.
Cosmos flowers are also
called autumn cherry blossoms,
and they're the prettiest
flowers in the fall.
Their name comes from an old word that
means harmony.
They can harmonize with all the other
flowers.
And any autumn grass will go just perfectly
with them in a flower arrangement.
So, tell me, do I look as pretty as the
cosmos flowers now?
Come on, am I cute?
Yeah.
Sheesh, took you long enough to say it.
Well, you sure look like you're having a
lot of fun, Billboard Brow.
You know, you're still nothing but a
hopeless little girl, Sakura.
So don't go strutting around like you're
hot stuff, got it?
Ami!
Sorry.
That head of yours is so
empty that I mistook it for
a vase and thought I'd
better put flowers in there.
No!
It's aconite, a shinobi flower.
I guess it really isn't that
poisonous, but still, you
might want to spit those
out when you get a chance.
I forgot to say only the root is
poisonous.
Ino is so great.
She knows practically everything.
Her clothes are so stylish, and she's way
cute.
She's even good with her shirt again.
And her ninjutsu is awesome, too.
Compared to that, I'm... nothing.
Hey, what's wrong?
Ino, if you're a cosmos flower,
then am I just a thorough wart?
Now why would you say that?
Well, let's see...
Actually, I don't think you're a flower at
all, Sakura.
You're still a bud waiting to bloom.
Yeah, you're right.
Say...
Ino?
Why did... you give me this ribbon?
What's it supposed to mean?
Let's just say that I
thought it would be a real
big waste for you to wilt
away as nothing but a bud.
I mean, how sad is it if flowers don't
ever bloom?
Hmm... Hmm...
Hmm...
I don't want to feel sorry for you.
Now, what are you so angry about?
Ino?
What's that in your head?
Don't you understand?
I don't know.
I don't know how to describe it.
A flower instead of a bud, always waiting
but never blooming.
So I set my sights on you, because I
wanted to be like you from the start.
You set an example for me that gave me a
goal to strive toward.
And it's because of that, that I made it
as far as I did.
It's why I'm here today.
But now, I don't want you to hold back.
What in the world is going on?
What do you mean?
Why are those two getting so worked up
just looking at each other?
He just can't see that he's exactly the
same way when it comes to Sasuke.
Well, Naruto, rivalry is a tricky
business.
Not that I would know.
Hmm?
Oh, hi there.
What else would I expect from my old rival
Kakashi?
Yet another glib, senseless statement.
Man, it burns me up when he acts so cool!
I understand, Sakura.
This time, we do this right.
No holding back.
A fair fight.
And I'm going to win!
Just a plain old jutsu?
This isn't just some Ninja Academy
graduation exam!
Do you really think you can beat me with a
basic ninja art like that?
No!
I'm not some crybaby anymore!
You play with fire, and you're gonna get
burned!
No matter how good Sakura is, Ino is just
as good!
This battle will rage for quite a while!
Man, since when did she get this strong?
I can do this!
I know I can!
You little...!
Whoa...
This has been going on so long.
They've been at it for ten minutes.
This isn't how this was supposed to go!
How can you be evenly matched with me?
Heh.
I guess you're right, Ino.
Your obsession with your looks and your
hair can't be surpassed.
I've been training too hard to worry about
that stuff.
You're gonna pay for that!
I've had enough of you making fun of me!
What an idiot.
Ino's falling for a trap.
She's so riled up by Sakura, there's no
telling what she'll do.
Oh man, I hate it when she's like this.
Huh.
Oh, I think she's totally lost it this
time.
That's it!
This ends right now!
Since neither combatant is able to
continue...
By double knockout, no one gets through
the fourth battle of this preliminary.
This match is over.
Sakura!
No way!
Very well then.
I've had grief.
Hey, Ino!
Sakura, no!
Sakura, wake up!
Are you okay?
Shhh.
I'm so ready.
After watching that last match,
I'm fired up.
So, this is another genin from the sand
village.
Go, Ten-ten!
This should be interesting to watch.
For the fifth match.
Ten-ten.
Temari.
Get ready.
So you're finally waking up, huh,
Sakura?
Come on, Ten-ten!
Use the power of you!
Nice, Lee!
Let's hear that support!
You can do it, Ten-ten!
Take her down, Ten-ten!
Our match is already over.
To think I tied with you.
I still can't believe that happened.
Here.
Guess you finally got a flower to bloom.
A beautiful flower.
Zero.
But Sakura... The next time you fight, you
won't just take the easy way by feinting.
And don't forget, we won't just hand over
Sasuke to you.
Understand, Sakura!?
Ready.
Oh yeah, well that goes double for you,
Ino, you ugly pig!
Whoa, that girl's really ruthless.
Oh, Denton.
Wasn't much of a match.
Kind of boring.
The winner of the fifth match,
Tamari.
Wait a second!
Hey, nice catch.
What is wrong with you?
She may have lost, but that is no way to
treat an opponent who has done her best!
I'll beat it.
And take that sack of garbage with you.
No, Lee!
Lee, leave her again!
What?
Not even close.
Lee, stop!
Wait, Gai-sensei!
Tamari, forget them.
The match is over, so get up here.
You won.
Why are you wasting your time with that
pathetic loser and his ridiculous mentor?
What?
A word of warning.
You sand villagers have no idea what Lee
is capable of.
Remember, he still hasn't fought yet.
So I'd be careful if I were you.
That kid's crazy picking a fight with
them.
Those sand village guys are trouble.
They're the last people I'd want to go up
against.
They do look almost unbeatable.
Don't worry, Naruto.
I'm sure you could take him.
Sakura?
What?
You're alright?
I never thought you'd be back so soon.
I'm fine, but never mind me.
It's you you should be thinking about.
Huh?
Me?
I don't have any injuries.
I haven't even fought yet.
What I meant was you
don't want to disgrace
yourself after you
worked so hard to get here.
Think of what Sasuke will say.
Oh.
Oh, right.
Here we go!
Let it be me!
Please let it be me!
No, it's my turn!
My turn!
Guess it's me.
Remember, he manipulates shadows.
Watch the shadows.
Heh.
You think I'd ever fall for a stupid jutsu
like that?
Yeah, okay!
Here we go, Shigemaru!
Make that little girl cry!
Oh man, this is such a drag.
I mean, give me a break.
I've gotta fight a girl.
Yeah, you just keep thinking that way,
little man.
I know what these guys are capable of from
the time we met them in the first place.
They fought for us during the second exam.
Problem is, I didn't get a look at her
jutsu.
And to make things worse, she saw mine.
Ready?
Oh well.
Sixth match.
Nothing I can do.
Shigemaru and Keen.
Begin.
Ninja Art!
Shadow Possession Jutsu!
Is that all you know?
If that's the only trick you've got,
this is going to be easier than I thought!
Bells?
Heh, oh please, not that old trick.
Lemme guess, next
you'll throw Senbon with
bells and Senbon without
bells at the same time.
You sure talk a lot, don't you?
Now I know to be careful to dodge all the
Senbon.
Not just the ones with the bells.
What?
Where?
Threats?
Too late!
Gah!
Shigemaru!
Well that didn't take long.
Hold on, don't be so sure.
He's not beaten yet.
Can't move my arm!
Heh, looks like my lame shadow jutsu was a
success after all.
But you haven't thrown any shadows.
No way I made sure of it!
Heh, you really still don't see it?
What do you mean?
Look at that thread you're holding.
Don't you find it a little strange that it
would even cast a shadow at this height?
Of course you didn't notice it because you
were concentrating on other things,
like killing me.
And now, so we mirror each other's
movements, so what?
A cute trick, but what do you gain by it?
Man, you're annoying.
You wouldn't!
You couldn't!
Yeah, like a game of chicken, let's see
who ducks first!
You're crazy!
Big deal, I'll do that too!
And that's what I call using your head.
The wise shinobi carefully scouts the
physical layout of the battlefield,
and never loses sight of his position on
it.
Winner of the sixth match, Shikamaru Nara.
Atta boy, Shikamaru!
Yeah, way to go!
Alright, moving on to the next match.
There's one sound village ninja left.
There's me, you, and me.
You, Naruto, Choji, Neji, Lee,
and that sand village guy.
Just don't put me up against him,
that's all I ask.
This year's rookies look like they could
be quite a challenge.
Yeah!
It's here!
It's here at last!
The moment I've been waiting for!
Finally, I get a chance to show what I've
got!
Look at that!
It's us against the kid!
Hey, Akamaru, I think you and I just won
the lottery!
Sure!
I am going to die of old age before I get
my turn!
I just want a chance to show Sakura what
I'm made of!
She's going to get tired of waiting!
All I want is a chance!
Is that too much to ask?
Lee, he's just like Guy used to be.
Good luck, Naruto!
Do your best!
You know it, Sakura!
It's your moment, Naruto.
Go on, show us.
Show us how much you've grown.
It's my time to shine!
Now, the seventh match.
Naruto Uzumaki and Kiba Inuzuka.
I've been waiting forever for this!
Sorry, Kiba.
Don't take it personally if I blow you
away.
That's just what I was going to say,
only not so politely.
Right, Akamaru?
Oh, yeah?
Well, talking's easy!
Let's see what you've got to say at the
end of the match!
Little squirt!
Wait a second, are you kidding me?
What's the puppy doing here?
He's just going to get in the way!
Deal with it!
I never go into battle without Akamaru!
Come on, isn't that against the rules or
something?
No.
Like Shino's bugs, they are a part of him.
He is within the rules.
Whatever, fine with me.
I do my best work with a handicap.
Ha!
We'll just see about that.
Akamaru, you stay right here and leave all
this to me.
I've got it.
Go on, Naruto!
You can't lose to this jerk!
Sorry, Kakashi.
But your boy doesn't stand a chance
against Kiba.
Not a chance.
Kiba's on my team.
I should be rooting for him.
But I really want to support Naruto.
Aw, man!
Kiba's so lucky!
When you're ready, you can begin.
Ninja art of beast mimicry all forced you
to!
Here I come!
This little guy's gonna be out for a
while.
You can call the match.
Thought as much.
Yeah, I thought Kiba might be too much for
him, but that was fast!
Oh, Naruto!
That was embarrassing!
See?
Told you.
What was that?
I blinked and it was over.
That kid's pitiful.
Don't ever...
Don't ever... Underestimate me!
The kid's come a long way.
Yeah, yeah, more tough talk!
Look at yourself in a mirror!
You're a mess!
Ha!
I just wanted to see what you've got!
Frankly, you hit like an old lady!
You have a better chance of winning this
if you send that puppy in to fight for you!
You're gonna regret that.
Come on, Akamaru!
Smoke grenades?
Take this!
I just want to...
This sucks!
I can't see a thing!
Gotta get out of this smoke and fast!
Have courage!
Yeah!
This fight is over!
Good doggy!
Way to...
Hey, Akamaru.
What are you doing?
You used a transformation jutsu!
You little... Get off!
Let go of me!
You smell even worse than the dog!
What'd you do with him?
Where is he?
He's right here!
How did you...
Okay... To balance a transformation
jutsu and a clone jutsu at the same time?
There's no way he should be able to do
that.
He's got his jutsu down, there's no doubt
about it.
Well, well.
Kid's better than I thought.
Wasn't that amazing?
Amazing!
That was amazing, Naruto!
Hehe!
What do you know?
I've gotten a little stronger,
I see.
But not nearly strong enough.
Because now I'm getting serious!
Oh?
Well, good!
I was hoping you would, because I want to
seriously knock you out!
Huh?
Ow!
Grrrr!
What the heck happened?
What was that thing you fed him?
How come all his fur just turned red?
Are you sure you want to stick around to
find out?
Hmm.
Food pills.
That's it.
Kiba's going in for the kill.
Let's go, Akamaru!
Waste mimicry!
Man-piece clones!
He's got a crazy look in his eyes all of a
sudden.
Hey, wait a second!
He took something!
No fair!
That's cheating!
He ought to be disqualified!
Food pills.
They're just another tool.
They're allowed.
Ah!
You're no help at all!
Now!
We're not beyond balance!
I can't counterattack!
All I can do is try to keep up my feet!
And stay out of their way!
Man-piece!
Ultimate Taijutsu!
Bang over bang!
I told you it was gonna get serious!
I will... I will be... Hokage!
I will!
How you gonna do that?
By lying flat on your face?
I got news for ya!
I'm gonna be Hokage!
Transform!
You've been here three years and can't do
a decent transformation?
It won't be fun!
I don't have to pretend to be Hokage!
You just wait!
Someday I'm gonna be Hokage for real!
Then you'll be sorry!
Ha!
You're right!
On what planet?
Come on!
Do you really believe a weakling like you
can be Hokage?
You must be weak in the head!
No...
You're wrong, Shiba!
I'm gonna make sure you don't get up
again!
I won't wait any longer!
I'll show you...
That's it!
I got you!
Now you're done!
Ok!
I'm gonna make sure you don't get up
again!
Gotta find a way to counter-attack!
Problem is, I don't know which one to
attack!
Which one's the real Kiva?
I can't tell them apart!
Wait a second, that's it!
Transform!
Very clever.
Okay, so I see you've gotten better at the
transformation jutsu.
But I still know which one is you.
You can't hide from me!
Wanna know why?
I can smell ya, kid.
There's just no getting past our sense of
smell.
Tough luck.
No way!
It's impossible!
I can't believe it!
So it's you!
Messing with me!
Atta boy!
Little squirt.
The smart shinobi is careful how he uses
his jutsu.
Otherwise it's liable to come back and
bite him on the butt.
Dummy!
Hey, that's my line.
Sort of.
Arguing with this kid is a waste of
energy.
I can't play his game.
Gotta keep calm.
Keep calm.
I still have the advantage.
I'm a lot faster than he is.
He can't keep up with me.
All I have to do is watch
for an opening, slip in
behind, and take him
down with my all-fours jutsu!
So, are you finally getting serious,
Kiba?
Good!
That means it's time to unveil something
special I've been saving!
My super secret killer move!
Ha!
Super secret killer move!
Get out of here!
It's a bluff!
Yeah?
Well, try me and find out!
Go for it!
Too late!
I got you now!
Gah!
And with his sense of smell a thousand
times more sensitive than average...
Nasty!
Whatever works, Naruto!
You slowed him down, at least!
I wish I could say I planned it!
Shadow clone jutsu!
You kicked me around pretty good so far!
Now it's payback time!
Gah!
No!
What?
Who's about to get you?
Gah!
The winner is... Naruto Uzumaki.
Woohoo!
Yes, Naruto!
That's my teammate!
Way to go!
Unbelievable!
Who would have thought he could beat Kiba?
A major upset.
It was nothing!
Piece of cake!
He's coming!
What do I do?
What do I...
Did you say something?
He nodded up?
I thought maybe...
Huh?
Hinata?
Well, well... Uh,
what's, uh, this?
It's a healing ointment.
For me?
What for?
Take it, Naruto.
Go ahead.
Hmm...
Hmph.
Thanks, Hinata.
That's, uh, real nice of you.
You have nothing to be ashamed of,
Kiba.
Who could have imagined he would be such a
strong opponent?
...
... ...
Silly Hinata.
Not a care in the world.
... ... ... ...
Whoa!
This stuff Hinata gave me works fast!
Here!
Wanna try it, Sakura?
Hmm?
Only your wounds will heal that quickly,
Naruto.
It's not the ointment.
It's the power of the Nine-Tailed Fox.
It never ceases to surprise me.
K-Kiba?
Here... here's some... healing ointment.
It's for you and Hakamaru.
Heh.
Forget about us.
You better start worrying about yourself,
Hinata.
Only six left.
Just you and Choji, Neji, Lee...
And then there are those two guys from the
Sound and Sand Villages.
Listen to me.
Be smart.
If they put you in with that guy from the
Sand Village...
You've got to forfeit the match.
...
Hinata...
Hmm.
This should be an interesting match
indeed.
I never thought that you and I would have
to face each other, Hinata.
Nor I, brother.
What'd she call him?
They're both descended from the Hyuga
Clan, one of the most ancient and
honorable families of the Hidden Leaf
Village.
Not actually brother and sister.
Okay, but they're related somehow,
right?
Yes.
Hinata belongs to the
family's main household,
directly descended
from the head of the clan.
While Neji's family is just a side branch
of the clan.
Still, they're family, and now they have
to fight each other.
I feel for them.
Must be hard.
It may not be as hard as it seems.
I have heard that for
many generations now there
has been some bad blood
between the two families.
All right.
You may begin when ready.
Before we do this, a word of advice.
Hinata, listen to me.
Withdraw now.
You know you were never meant to be a
ninja.
You're too kind and gentle.
You seek harmony and avoid conflict.
You have no confidence.
You feel inferior to everyone else here.
It would have been better for you to
simply remain a genin.
But to register for the Chunin exams,
you need a team of three people.
You never even wanted to take part in
these exams, but Shino and Kiba did.
And you couldn't bear to let your
teammates down.
Could you?
No!
You're wrong!
I wanted... I had to find out...
I did it because I wanted to see if I
could change.
People can't change no matter how hard
they try.
They can't run away from their true
nature.
A failure will always be a failure.
I understand these things because I see
the world clearly with my Byakugan.
Despite your brave words, what you're
really thinking is that you'd like to run.
Run as far away from here as you can.
No!
You're wrong!
You're wrong about me!
Byakugan?
It's the kekegenkai or bloodline trait of
the Hyuga.
A visual jutsu like Sasuke's Sharingan.
You're wrong.
Byakugan!
Just one moment ago, in the
slightest of movements, your
gaze drifted toward the
upper left corner of the room.
I saw, at that moment, you were thinking
of your past.
Your bitter past.
And then, almost immediately after,
your gaze drifted to the lower right.
It was a mere flicker
of the eyes, but to me it
revealed all of your mental
and physical suffering.
You're seeing your old self.
And wondering if your life has prepared
you for this moment.
You're picturing the outcome of the
battle.
You see yourself losing.
And the way you're holding your arms in
front of your body like that?
It tells me that you're trying to build a
wall between us.
To keep me at bay.
Shall we go on?
That familiar gesture of putting your
finger to your lips.
I know that it's a desperate attempt to
suppress your rising panic.
Made all the more desperate because you
know it's futile.
Whether you admit it or not, you already
know.
That does it!
Who gave you the right to tell her what
she can or can't be?
Go on, Hinata!
Show this guy he's wrong!
You're just gonna stand there and take
that?
Do something!
You're driving me crazy!
Annoying little test.
You're right, Naruto.
Thank you.
The look in her eye has changed.
If you don't forfeit the match,
you know what will happen.
I won't run away!
No way!
I never go back on my word!
That's the way of the ninja!
No more hiding!
The other side!
Very well, then.
I have on my team the man
who is probably the strongest
genin ever to come out
of the Hidden Leaf Village.
That man.
Neji Hyuga.
...
This is the man!
And this is the man who will bring the
power of the Did she get him?
No way!
She hardly touched him!
Even so, a glancing blow is enough.
That is what makes the Hyuga clan the most
formidable of fighters.
What does?
What are you talking about?
Their Taijutsu is a unique one that's been
passed down for generations.
It's not the kind of taijutsu Lee and I
employ.
We tend to concentrate on inflicting
external damage.
We use crushing blows to raise contusions
and break limbs, pounding our enemy.
The Hugo way is to attack
their opponent's internal organs
and the chakra network
through which the chakra flows.
Their way is more... subtle.
Perhaps not as thrilling to watch.
But it gradually takes effect,
with devastating results.
But Sensei, how do they know where to
strike their opponent?
I mean, the chakra network is invisible to
the eye, right?
So how do they know exactly where to land
their blows?
You're forgetting their Byakugan.
There are few things invisible to those
eyes.
What's more, when they strike a blow, it's
a little different from a normal attack.
A small but intense burst of their own
chakra is released from their hand.
It drills into the opponent's body,
directly attacking his chakra network.
Yeah!
Get him!
So that's it, huh?
That's all there is to the main branch's
power?
Wait, what is going on?
I mean, I saw Hinata hit Neji perfectly!
I'm not done yet.
What's with this kid?
But... you mean... all this
time you... That's right.
I could see your chakra points the whole
time.
Huh?
What is he talking about?
On the chakra network, there are...
Chakra points.
And each are only about the size of the
head of a pin.
Hitting one directly can affect chakra
flow, either halting it or increasing it,
depending on how the attacker strikes the
chakra points.
Theoretically, doing
so allows a ninja to gain
complete control over
an opponent's chakra flow.
But these chakra points... they're
undetectable even to my Sharingan eye.
And even beyond his ability
to see the chakra points, he
can target them accurately,
even during intense battle.
Look, Hinata.
I'm completely out of your league,
and that won't change.
You may not like it, but it's a fact.
From the instant you said you wouldn't run
anymore, your fate was sealed.
You were destined for failure.
Forfeit this match.
I... I never...
Go... back...
On... my word.
I'm not going to run away!
Because that, too, is my nindo... my ninja
way.
I had no idea... that Hinata's as tough as
she is.
She is a lot like you.
You know, come to think of it... she is
always watching you.
Huh?
Hinata!
She has reached her limit.
One more blow, and she's done.
Go, Hinata!
You can do it!
Naruto...
Strength has come back into her eyes.
I've been watching you.
I've been watching you closely for many
years now.
I wonder why.
When I watch you, I feel full of courage.
I feel that I can keep going.
That I can succeed.
That even I am worth something.
Hinata!
Hinata...
Hinata used to be a quitter.
But I can see that she's changed.
I have never seen such a look
of... of fierceness in her eyes before.
Hinata... Eh.
Not at all.
Until now, I have always done the
watching.
But...
Now?
Finally, you're the one watching me,
and I'll show you what I can do.
Hinata... Hinata...
Hinata...
Hinata... And from the
very start, you're finished.
Hinata, you've done enough.
You lost the match, but you've become a
new person in the process.
You did great.
It's too bad, but after that blow to the
heart, Hinata is done.
Since she's no longer able
to continue this match... No!
Don't stop this match!
Naruto!
What on earth are you doing?
Hinata's had it.
You can see she's unconscious,
can't you?
What do you think you're doing?
If you continue to fight, you're going to
die.
It doesn't matter.
I'm not going to let myself look bad.
Not now.
Not in front of the person I admire most.
Who's finally seeing the real me.
I'm far from finished!
Give up the tough guy act.
I can tell you're barely standing.
You've been carrying a very heavy burden.
Having been born to the main branch of the
Hyuga clan.
No, you're wrong, brother.
You've got it backwards.
You see, I can tell... that you're the
one... you're suffering much more than I.
I what?
You're the one who's all
torn up... about the fate
of the main and side
branches of the Hyuga clan.
Grrrr!
Neji, no!
The match is over!
Neji, get a hold of yourself.
You promised me you wouldn't let this
whole head family thing get you riled up.
Why are you and the other Jonin butting
in?
The head family gets special treatment,
huh?
Hinata!
You okay?
Hey!
Na... Naruto... do you think... I changed?
Maybe a little?
Hey, you!
Loser!
I have two pieces of advice for you.
First of all, if you
intend to call yourself
a shinobi, stop that
stupid cheering of yours.
It's disgraceful.
And second, once a failure, always a
failure.
You can't change that.
We'll just see about that!
What are you doing?
Naruto, I get where you are coming from,
believe me.
But the rules say, all fighting must be
done officially in a match.
The loser beating the gifted genius
through sheer willpower.
Now would not that make for an exciting
match?
Even if, I am the one who is going to have
to fight Neji.
I am the one who is going to have to fight
Neji.
Alright, fine!
You win, Lee!
Oh no, she's going into cardiac arrest.
Was he really trying to kill her?
I wouldn't waste your
time glaring at me,
when you really should
be taking care of her.
Get a medic!
And hurry up!
We're coming!
She has no pulse.
It's very serious.
She's got ten minutes
and... That's best.
Let's get her to the emergency room,
now!
Stand back!
Hinata...
Hinata, I give you my word.
I vow to win!
Whoa, Choji.
Glad I'm here.
I'm not you.
I mean, you've still got the toughest ones
left.
I'm not feeling so good.
Maybe I ought to go ahead and forfeit
right now.
What?
You know, if you win, I'll take you for
barbecue.
What?
Come on!
Choji, come on, don't worry.
If it gets bad, we'll step in and stop the
fight just like with Hinata, okay?
Think of it.
All the short ribs you
can eat... That's a low blow.
Playing on his weak spot?
That's a low blow.
When did he step in and stop the fight
anyway?
Now you're talking!
All you can eat!
Bring it on!
I'm still curious about that Neji guy.
Yeah, that might work.
Where are you going?
Just doing a little recon.
I'll be back.
Hey, you!
Hmm?
How come you're all by yourself?
Why aren't you hanging with your buddies?
Huh?
What's it to you?
Well, well.
Touchy.
So tell me something about this guy Neji.
I get the feeling we didn't see the full
extent of his powers in the last fight,
did we?
So what's his story?
I'm gonna pulverize him!
That's his story!
I'm like a nice guy.
I like you.
Well, don't take this the wrong way,
but I don't like you!
This kid is toast.
Now then, we'll continue the competition.
Alright!
This time you'll be picked, I just know
it!
You ready, Lee?
No!
Huh?
I have been waiting so long, I do not
care!
I might as well go last!
Yes sir!
Please take this to your Why does he have
so much power?!
Come back here!
Well, come on.
Let's do this.
Safe again!
It worked like a charm.
I knew if I said I want to be last,
I would be next.
I simply applied the principle
which states that sometimes
the surest way to hit something
is to stop trying to hit it.
It is a form of reverse psychology.
Hoo-ah!
That's my student!
I absolutely was not going to be last,
no matter what!
Ha-ha!
I sure fooled them, did I not?
Fooled who?
Now then, listen carefully.
A piece of advice before you begin.
Sir!
Look.
You see that gourd that Gaara is wearing?
Watch out.
There's something weird about it.
Good advice, sir!
Don't write it down!
What are you thinking?
After all, you're not going to have a
chance.
You don't have time to read any notes
during the match, are you?
Ah!
More good advice!
He just figured that out about the gourd?
I hopefully will be all right.
Now, rock and roll!
Yeah!
I knew that sooner or later we would have
to meet, and I'm glad it is sooner.
Why are you in such a hurry?
All right, then.
If you are both ready, begin.
Ah!
Leave her again!
Huh?
Ah!
Huh!
It's you, Yuu.
Musashi!
Where were you?
I forgot you were there!
Way to go!
Yeah, it's you!
Ah... Huh?
Sakuya!
Come on, be brave!
What the hell?
What are you doing?
Are you OK?
Actually...
Even as fast as he is, Lee can't get
anywhere close to him.
The sand!
He's using it as a shield!
He's not doing it.
The sand is protecting him of its own
accord.
Huh?
It's almost like a living thing.
It'll come to Gaara's defense without his
doing anything.
That's why Gaara's never been injured.
No one can get at him.
No one's ever even been able to touch him.
How is he doing it?
He's not moving a muscle!
Well, is that all?
I hope you haven't finished entertaining
me.
We haven't had enough...
blood.
I don't get it.
He's only using taijutsu!
Can't he see that's never going to work?
Why doesn't he get some distance?
And use ninjutsu?
Yes, that might be a good idea.
That is, if he had any.
Huh?
Lee has no ninjutsu or genjutsu skills at
all.
You're kidding!
Oh, that's nothing.
You should have seen how hopeless he was
when I first met him.
No talent whatsoever.
Really?
I can't believe it.
Ah!
Ah...
All right, Lee.
Take him off.
Ah!
But, Gai-sensei!
You said that was only
as a last resort when the
lives of very important
people were at stake!
That's right, I did.
But this can't be...
This is an exception.
Really?
How old-fashioned.
Leg weights?
Basic training equipment.
Ah!
That is better!
Now I will be able to move freely!
Come on, you really think
you'll be able to get through
Gaara's defenses just by dropping
a couple of pounds of weight?
Ah!
Gai, you are too much.
All right!
Now go!
Yes, sir!
Ah!
So close!
I can see that Lee had no aptitude for
ninjutsu or genjutsu.
So he skipped them
and focused all of his
time and energy into
developing his taijutsu.
That way we turned his disadvantage into a
blessing.
Now he doesn't need those other things to
win.
Because he's transformed himself into the
world's greatest taijutsu specialist.
Ah!
I don't believe it!
Gaara's been hurt!
Impossible!
Whoa!
That's scary!
And I thought he was quick on his feet
before!
He's been that fast all this time?
Yes, Lee!
Let the power of youth explode!
Right!
Over here!
No, here!
Good!
A direct hit!
It makes me dizzy just trying to keep
track of him!
Hmph!
Uh-oh.
Yeah, uh-oh is right!
Your friend with the eye makeup is getting
the stuffing beaten out of him!
That isn't what I was talking about,
kid.
Huh?
What?
He encased himself in sand, huh?
Things must be bad.
I haven't seen that look on his face for a
long time...
As I thought.
His inner demon has been awakened...
My speed will not be enough.
He is impossible to get at behind those
sand defenses!
But maybe if I can get him up off the
ground and away from the sand...
then hit him hard from
above... ...with the lotos.
Hmph!
Get ready!
That's right, Lee.
Good work.
That flimsy shield of sand won't protect
it from your high-speed lotus.
What are you waiting for?
Okay, you asked for it!
Try this!
What an incredible series of kicks.
Even an ordinary lotus puts an enormous
strain on the body.
Let alone this.
You've got to finish him off now!
Now take this!
Primary lotus!
It is over.
I got him!
Right on!
Amazing!
He really did it!
No, I don't believe it!
You did it!
Way to go, Lee!
Izzy, that guy isn't dead, is he?
I don't believe it!
But how?
When did he do it?
It was when you closed your eyes to pray.
Huh?
Ah!
No!
The fourth kid is helpless.
He doesn't have anything left.
Gara's left.
Gara's just toying with him now.
Dummy, why bother?
You'll never be a ninja.
We'll do.
There's no way a kid who can't even do
ninjutsu can ever be a ninja.
Yes, I can.
Whatever.
I don't get why you're even at this ninja
academy when you can't do ninjutsu or
genjutsu and you're even worse than
average at taijutsu.
It's idiotic.
Hey, you know what everyone here is
calling you, don't you?
Dork Lee!
Hey Lee!
Where are you going?
Get back in line!
So that's the no talent overachiever I've
heard so much about.
Yeah, he kind of reminds me of someone.
Especially around the eyebrows.
Rock Lee.
The dork with nothing going for him but a
little lousy taijutsu.
But you kept at it, didn't you?
You kept practicing your little lousy
taijutsu.
As of today, you are all genin.
So now tell me, why have you done it?
What are your goals?
Hmm?
Oh, me me sensei, me!
Yes, Ten-ten.
I want to be a great and
powerful ninja to walk in
the footsteps of the
legendary kunoichi Tsunade.
I see.
How about me sensei?
I want to show I can be a splendid ninja
as well.
Even if I do not have ninjutsu or
genjutsu.
I want to prove it to the whole world!
Lee will struggle on long after the point
where anyone else would have quit.
If I cannot do 1,200 without a mistake,
then it is 2,000 kicks!
1,117!
1,118!
1,119!
1,100!
Ah!
Lee!
Haha, taking a break already?
Huh?
What is it, guy sensei?
If it is about my messing up on the last
assignment, I said I was sorry.
Lee!
It's true you are different from Neji and
the others.
You have no gift for ninjutsu or genjutsu,
and your taijutsu needs work.
But then again, you have a gift that Neji
doesn't have.
Not as flashy, but perhaps even more
important.
You do not have to make me feel better!
You idiot!
You think I'd waste my time with that?
No, all I'm saying is
that you have the gift of
perseverance, and that's
what makes you a genius too!
What is that true sensei?
I wonder...
I used to think so.
I used to believe that if I
just trained harder than Neji,
two or three times harder, I
would make myself strong enough.
But now, I am not so sure.
I do not know if I will ever be able to
work hard enough to beat real talent.
That is why I am always taking on Neji.
I keep thinking all of my efforts will pay
off, but it is always the same.
I am no match for him at all.
Every time we have a ninja mission,
my legs begin shaking.
I do not know if I can take it.
Sometimes it seems like the whole thing is
pointless.
Like I am a loser, and I will always be a
loser.
I do not know what to do.
You are right.
All the effort is pointless, if you do not
believe in yourself.
You know, Lee, we are a lot alike,
you and I.
You mean the eyebrows?
No, I do not mean our eyebrows.
You see, I was a loser too once.
What?
You were a loser?
Oh, yes indeed.
But I made myself the equal of any ninja,
even Kakashi.
And I did it through effort.
You say you want to show the world you can
be a splendid ninja, even if you do not
have all the gifts that others are blessed
with.
That is your nendo, your ninja way,
right?
Well, I think that is a fine goal.
As fine a goal as I have ever heard,
and one worth sticking to.
Do not let anything steer you off the path
you have drawn for yourself.
Forge ahead to the end.
Stick to it, Lee.
Make me proud.
Be everything you can be.
Will you do that for me, Lee?
Yes, sir!
Gai-sensei, thank you!
I will make you proud, sensei!
I will forge ahead, follow my path to the
end, and become the ninja I know I can be!
Lee's smiling!
He's running for his life, but he's still
smiling!
Yes, but now it's Gaara's turn to run.
The Leaf Village lotus blooms twice.
But... no, Gai, you didn't.
Yes, Kakashi, I did.
So that genin, that
boy, is able to open the
Eight Inner Gates and
use the Hidden Lotus?
That's correct.
Well, if that isn't the most...
Okay, what exactly are these Eight Inner
Gates you're talking about?
And the Hidden Lotus?
There are gates along the
chakra network, located at those
points in the body where the
chakra is most heavily concentrated.
Starting at the head, they are the gate of
opening, the gate of rest, of life,
of pain, of closing, of joy, of shock,
and the gate of death.
These are what are called the Eight Inner
Gates.
Their purpose is to limit the flow of
chakra through the body.
But the lotus exerts
tremendous pressure on these
limiters, eventually
forcing the gates open.
This releases the restraints on the
chakra.
The result being that a person's strength
can be increased tenfold, or more.
The Primary Lotus opens only the first
gate, the gate of opening.
Wait a minute.
Just the Primary Lotus almost destroyed
him.
He could barely move.
What's gonna happen to him if he takes it
farther?
Exactly.
By opening all Eight Gates, you could
attain power beyond even the Hokage's.
The only drawback is...
You'd die.
I don't know what this boy means to you,
guy.
But I shouldn't have to tell you that we
never bring our personal feelings into play.
I wouldn't have thought you were capable
of this.
You have no right.
You know nothing about him.
Nothing at all.
That boy has something important to prove.
And he's determined to prove it,
even at the cost of his life.
I am not going to be the only one to lose
here!
Guy-sensei, please let this work!
It is now or never!
He's opened the third gate, the gate of
life.
Now he'll attack.
Oh no, not yet.
The fourth gate!
Gate of Pain!
Open!
It's faster than ever.
Huh?
Whoa!
Got us!
Where'd they... go?
Huh?
Up there!
My armor... can't withstand this pounding!
You are a tough one!
Try this!
His muscles are tearing themselves apart!
Is that really Lee?
But when?
How?
One more and we are finished!
The fifth gate!
Gate of Closing!
Open!
No human could move like this!
Impossible to defend myself!
Are you watching, Neji?
Are we saving this ace in the hole to use
against you?
See what you have to look forward to?
Huh?
No!
The shield can't keep up!
He's in trouble!
It is loaded!
So fast!
I couldn't see a thing!
Unbelievable!
He did it!
Kana!
Is it over?
Huh?
What's that?
Down there!
Unbelievable!
He cushioned his fall by turning that
gourd into sand!
Impossible!
He not only survived the hidden lotus,
he is able to go on the attack!
Sand coffin!
You have been...
NOOOOOOO!
Now you die!
But why?
He failed!
Why he did that?
Save him!
Because he's...
He's my student.
And also because he is precious to me.
That's a sentiment that Gaara couldn't
even begin to understand.
I quit.
Huh?
It can't be.
After all that, he shouldn't be able to
move, let alone stand up.
No, Lee.
It's alright.
It's all over now.
Anyway, you're in no condition to...
Lee...
Oh, Lee...
What have I done?
He's out cold.
Nothing keeping him up but sheer
willpower.
You are a splendid ninja.
The winner is Gaara.
Right?
... I can't believe it...
Lee lost to him?!
Hurry!
This boy needs attention.
You're his teacher, aren't you?
I am.
What is it?
Will you come with me?
Careful with him.
That's right, easy.
The boy's breathing is faint, but steady.
There are bone fractures and muscle tears
throughout his body.
He's facing a long and difficult
rehabilitation.
But I'm afraid that's not the worst of it.
His left arm and leg in particular have
suffered massive damage.
I'm sorry, I know how much it means to you
both.
But he'll never fight again.
His days as a shinobi are over.
Lee...
Oh, forgive me.
I couldn't bear the thought of you losing.
It was all my fault.
I should have stopped it.
Forgive me.
Lee!
It's not true.
It can't be true.
Easy for you to say it's over.
What about Bushy Brow?
What's he supposed to do now?
Failure?
I thought you said we could win.
I thought you were going to show how a
failure can win.
That's enough, Naruto.
But Sensei, it isn't fair.
All he ever wanted was to prove himself
against Sasuke and Neji.
And maybe that's what led to his downfall.
But you're wrong about one thing,
Naruto.
It wasn't just Sasuke and Neji he was
thinking of.
It was you too.
That's right.
He risked everything just for the hope of
meeting you in combat.
Remember that.
Be worthy of his sacrifice.
Fate will never smile
on the fortunes of a ninja
who seeks victory by
falling on his own sword.
Or demanding that others fall on theirs.
So, the worst didn't happen after all.
Good to have you back, Gaara.
Gai.
What I said earlier, it was out of line.
I was being a self-righteous fool.
I realize now that if
I'd been in your shoes,
I probably couldn't
have stopped him either.
Come on, Gai.
Let's go up.
They can't start the next match with us
standing here.
Right.
Now then, the last two competitors.
Will you please step forward?
So, it's finally my turn.
Just keep your eyes on the prize.
All-you-can-eat barbecue.
My job is to survive the main tournament
and battle Sasuke.
Isn't that right, Lord Orochimaru?
I wouldn't want to disappoint you.
I begin to see through your design.
The reason you set us against Sasuke,
but forbid us from killing him.
The curse you put on him.
We were your pawns, weren't we,
my lord?
Put here merely to test the limits of his
abilities.
It's not Sasuke's life you want.
It's Sasuke himself.
You played us all for fools.
Even me.
All right.
The tenth and final match.
Begin.
You can do it!
Fatso!
Okay!
I'm gonna finish this match!
It's only gonna take about two seconds!
And then I'm coming after you,
Eno!
Fine, Fatso.
If you want this match to end quickly,
I'll just win it quickly.
You're gonna go down hard, you mummified
weirdo!
Ninja Arts!
Expansion Jutsu!
Now the Hidden Leaf Style Taijutsu!
This will protect my ears from his
attacks!
And crush him like a bug!
Human Boulder!
Chubby's Rule!
Yeah!
He barely has any control over where he's
going!
Now to end this!
It's no use!
My ears are covered!
You're so wrong.
Uwaaaaaah!
See, the human body is 70% water,
and water can transmit sound waves.
In other words...
When it comes to my attacks, your whole
body is basically one big ear.
The winner is... Dosukinuta.
Lord Orochimaru.
Or rather, Orochimaru.
Now do you see?
I'm more than a mere puppet.
Hey, are you alright?
Meat.
I wanna eat some meat.
That's our Choji.
Always thinking with his stomach.
Even though he lost, the least we can do
is take him out for some barbecue beef.
It's finally over.
At long last, we can begin the final
rounds.
And with that match, the third exam
preliminaries are now finished.
Вы на моего солнца.
I can't believe it...
I didn't know you were such a precious
student.
I'll be very grateful if I have to say
this much in the future.
You, too, as well.
I'm extremely grateful that you've become
an awesome student.
I think I'm the best student I've ever
met.
And I'm always thankful for John.
And for all the people in the world.
And after all this happening, I'd like to
say one thing to my friends and family.
If you are a great student, please give
the best of yourself to everyone.
See you soon.
It's okay now, because everyone is in the
middle of my hand.
I want to cry, I want to run away.
If I forget my happiness, I'll sing a
song.
The light is born, the darkness is born.
Two are one.
Harmonia.
Penetration.
Hey, can you hear me?